Chiho Choi, Ph.D.

CONTACT INFROMATION

Honda Research Institute USA Inc. Website 70 Rio Robles, San Jose, CA 95134 LinkedIn chihochoi@outlook.com Google Scholar

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests span the fields of computer vision, machine learning, and robotics, focusing on understanding and prediction of human behavior in highly interactive environments. In this area, I build a new perspective for the safe operation of autonomous systems designed to cooperate with humans.

• Behavior Reasoning

- Motion Prediction
- Activity Forecasting
- Relational Inference

- Uncertainty Modeling
- Interactive Planning
- Human Pose Prediction Pose Estimation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Honda Research Institute (HRI) USA

San Jose, CA, USA

Senior Scientist

July 2021 – Present

• Leading multiple projects on understanding of human action, intention, and future behavior.

Scientist

February 2018 – June 2021

• Worked on recognition, reasoning, and prediction of human states and behaviors in multi-agent interacting environments.

HERE Technologies

Chicago, IL, USA

Intern

May 2017 – August 2017

- Worked on traffic scene understanding (detection and recognition) for automated driving.
- Proposed a solution to learn from imbalanced data for generic machine learning systems.
- Supervisor: Dr. Xiang Ma and Prof. Xin Chen

EDUCATION

Purdue University

West Lafayette, IN, USA

January 2018

- Ph.D., Electrical and Computer Engineering
- Specialization: deep learning, 3D vision, recognition, tracking
- Committee members: Karthik Ramani, Stanley H. Chan, Mireille Boutin, Jeffrey M. Siskind

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA, USA

May 2013

- M.S., Electrical Engineering
- Specialization: 3D shape matching, registration
- Advisor: Prof. Suya You, Department of Computer Science

Hanyang University **B.S.**, Electronics and Computer Engineering Seoul, Korea

February 2011

• Minor: Mechanical Engineering

PUBLICATIONS

I have published 17 peer-reviewed papers (13 as a first or corresponding author) in the field of Computer

Vision (CVPR – 2 oral & 1 poster, ICCV – 6 posters), Machine Learning (NeurIPS, ICLR), Robotics (ICRA, IROS, CoRL), and Control (ACC). The full list of papers is as follows:

Refereed Papers

- [C17] H. Girase*, H. Gang*, S. Malla, J. Li, A. Kanehara, K. Mangalam, and C. Choi. "LOKI: Long Term and Key Intentions for Trajectory Prediction". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2021, to appear.
- [C16] J. Li, F. Yang, H. Ma, S. Malla, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "RAIN: Reinforced Hybrid Attention Inference Network for Motion Forecasting". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2021, to appear.
- [C15] C. Choi*, J. H. Choi*, J. Li, and S. Malla "Shared Cross-Modal Trajectory Prediction for Autonomous Driving". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2021, Oral presentation (4.2% acceptance rate). *arXiv:* 2011.08436
- [C14] S. Malla, C. Choi, and B. Dariush "Social-STAGE: Spatio-Temporal Multi-Modal Future Trajectory Forecast". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* 2021. arXiv: 2011.04853
- [C13] J. Li, F. Yang, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "EvolveGraph: Multi-Agent Trajectory Prediction with Dynamic Relational Reasoning". *In Proceedings of the Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)* 2020. arXiv: 2003.13924
- [C12] C. Choi, S. Malla, A. Patil, and J. H. Choi. "DROGON: A Trajectory Prediction Model based on Intention-Conditioned Behavior Reasoning". *In Proceedings of the Conference on Robot Learning* (CoRL) 2020. arXiv:1908.00024
- [C11] I. Dwivedi, S. Malla, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "SSP: Single Shot Future Trajectory Prediction". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)* 2020. arXiv: 2004.05846
- [C10] S. Malla, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "TITAN: Future Forecast using Action Priors". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2020, Oral presentation (5.7% acceptance rate). arXiv:2003.13886
- [C9] S. Bae, D. Saxena, A. Nakhaei, C. Choi, K. Fujimura, and S. Moura. "Cooperation-Aware Lane Change Maneuver in Dense Traffic based on Model Predictive Control with Recurrent Neural Network". *In Proceedings of the American Control Conference (ACC)* 2020. arXiv:1909.05665
- [C8] C. Choi and B. Dariush. "Looking to Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast". In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019. arXiv: 1905.08855
- [C7] C. Choi and B. Dariush. "Learning to Infer Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast". In the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops 2019.
- [C6] Y. Yao, M. Xu, C. Choi, D. Crandall, E. Atkins, and B. Dariush. "Egocentric Vision-based Future Vehicle Localization for Intelligent Driving Assistance Systems". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* 2019.
- [C5] M. Liu, F. Yao, C. Choi, A. Sinha, and K. Ramani. "Deep Learning 3D Shapes Using Alt-az Anisotropic 2-Sphere Convolution". *In Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)* 2019.
- [C4] C. Choi, S. Kim, and K. Ramani. "Learning Hand Articulations by Hallucinating Heat Distribution". In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2017.
- [C3] C. Choi, S. H. Yoon, C. N. Chen, and K. Ramani. "Robust Hand Pose Estimation during the Interaction with an Unknown Object". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2017.
- [C2] C. Choi*, A. Sinha*, and K. Ramani (* Co-first Author, order changed for emphasis). "DeepHand:

- Robust Hand Pose Estimation by Completing a Matrix Imputed with Deep Features". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2016.
- [C1] C. Choi, A. Sinha, J. H. Choi, S. Jang, and K. Ramani. "A Collaborative Filtering Approach to Real-Time Hand Pose Estimation". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision* (ICCV) 2015.

Non-Refereed Papers

- [T4] S. Su, C. Peng, J. Shi, and **C. Choi**. "Potential Field: Interpretable and Unified Representation for Trajectory Prediction". *November* 2019. arXiv:1911.07414
- [T3] S. Malla, I. Dwivedi, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "NEMO: Future Object Localization Using Noisy Ego Priors". *September 2019. arXiv:1909.08150*
- [T2] C. Choi, S. Kim, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Embedding Compressive Layers in Deep Neural Networks". *Technical Report, Purdue University, May 2017*.
- [T1] C. Choi and S. You. "Dense and Reliable Shape Matching using 3D Particle Filtering". *Technical Report, University of Southern California, May 2013.*

Thesis

[D1] C. Choi. "Computational Learning for Hand Pose Estimation". Ph.D. Dissertation, Purdue University, Jan 2018.

PATENT APPLICATIONS

- [P21] J. Li, H. Gang, H. Ma, and C. Choi. "System and Method for Important Object Identification with Semi-Supervised Learning". Application pending.
- [P20] H. Girase, H. Gang, S. Malla, J. Li, A. Kanehara, and C. Choi. "System and Method for Providing Long Term Key Intentions for Trajectory Prediction". Application pending.
- [P19] H. Ma, J. Li, and C. Choi. "System and Method for Completing Continual Multi-Agent Trajectory Forecasting". Application pending.
- [P18] C. Choi, S. Malla, and S. Bae. "System and Method for Completing Trajectory from Agent-Augmented Environments". Application pending.
- [P17] J. Li and C. Choi. "System and Method for Reinforced Hybrid Attention for Motion Forecasting". Application pending.
- [P16] S. Malla, C. Choi, and B. Dariush. "System and Method for Providing Social-Stage Spatio-Temporal Multi-Modal Future Forecasting". Application pending.
- [P15] C. Choi. "System and Method for Shared Cross-Modal Trajectory Prediction". Application pending.
- [P14] J. Li and C. Choi. "Systems and Methods for Heterogeneous Multi-Agent Multi-Modal Trajectory Prediction with Evolving Interaction Graphs". Application pending.
- [P13] I. Dwivedi, S. Malla, C. Choi, and Behzad Dariush. "System for Single Shot Prediction using Composite Fields and Method Thereof". Application pending.
- [P12] S. Malla, C. Choi, and Behzad Dariush. "System and Method for Future Forecasting using Action Priors". Application pending.
- [P11] S. Su and C. Choi. "System and Method for Providing an Interpretable and Unified Representation for Trajectory Prediction". Application pending.
- [P10] A. Nakhaei, K. Fujimura, C. Choi, S. Bae, D. Saxena. "System and Method for Providing Cooperation-Aware Lane Change Control in Dense Traffic". US 16/844331
- [P9] S. Malla and C. Choi. "System and Method for Providing Future Object Localization". US 16/828343
- [P8] C. Choi. "Trajectory Prediction". No. 16/524821

[P7] Y. Yao, M. Xu, C. Choi, and B. Dariush. "System and Method for Egocentric-vision based Future Vehicle Localization". Publication No. 16/386964

[P6] C. Choi. "Methods and Apparatuses for Future Trajectory Forecast". US 11/062141

[P5] X. Chen, X. Ma, S. Sood, and C. Choi. "Semi-automatic Training Data Selection based on High-dimensional Data Projection to Subspaces". Application pending.

[P4] X. Chen, X. Ma, S. Sood, and C. Choi. "Deep Neural Machine for Lane Marking Style Classification based on Unwrapped Perspective Images". Application pending.

[P3] X. Chen, X. Ma, S. Sood, and C. Choi. "Deep Neural Machine for Lane Marking Color and Material Classification based on Image Patches". Application pending.

[P2] A. Sinha, C. Choi, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Method of training neural networks for hand pose detection". US 10/503270

[P1] A. Sinha, C. Choi, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Method and System for Hand Pose Estimation". US 10/318008

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Students Supervised

May 2021 – Present
May 2021 – Present
January 2021 – Present
January 2021 – Present
September 2019 – May 2021
January 2021 – April 2020
July 2019 – December 2020
May 2020 – August 2020
June 2019 – September 2019
May 2018 – August 2018

Teaching Assistant

• Purdue University

January 2015 – May 2015

ME 444: Computer-aided Design and Rapid Prototyping

Introduction to advanced computer-aided design for product design, modeling, and prototyping.

• University of Southern California

August 2012 – December 2012

CSCI 588 (graduate-level course): Specification and Design of User Interface Software

A design and implementation of user interface software relating to human/computer interaction.

INVITED TALKS

Guest Lecturer, Purdue University

December 2017

• Introduction to Pose Estimation – Probabilistic models in computer vision

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Organizing Chair

• 1st Workshop on Multi-Agent Interaction and Relational Reasoning in conjunction with ICCV 2021

Publication Committee

• Honda Research Institute USA

February 2020 – Present

Program Committee / Reviewer

• International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021, 2022

- IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2021, 2022
- Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2020, 2021
- IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2021
- IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019, 2021
- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2021
- IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021
- Association for Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2020, 2021
- Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) 2018, 2020
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2020
- IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV) 2020
- ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) 2019
- IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)
- IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Vehicles (T-IV)
- IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (T-IP)
- IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (T-MM)

HORNORS

National Science and Technology Scholarship from *Ministry of Education, Science and Technology*, Korea 2003 - 2010

MEDIA COVERAGE

- Looking to Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast, ICCV Daily Magazine, October 30, 2019.
- AI Can Predict the Future Location of Vehicles, NVIDIA NEWS Center, September 27, 2018.
- Freeing Our Fingers: Handing Over VR's Toughest Challenge to GPUs, NVIDIA Blog, August 24, 2016.
- AI and VR: New Experiments at Purdue University, ENGINEERING.com, June 30, 2016
- DeepHand motion tracking enters the VR arms race, New Atlas, June 23, 2016
- New tool for virtual and augmented reality uses 'deep learning', Purdue News, June 22, 2016.

REFERENCES

Available Upon Request